Okay, so let's discuss the Agile
prioritization techniques.
There's several prioritization or several
ways of prioritizing the work in Agile.
There's just a few that you need to know
for the PMP exam.
So let's cover each of these.
The Kano model, something
called the Kano model,
developed by someone by
the name of Noriaki Kano.
And what Kano refers to, he tries to
basically rate the customer's satisfaction.
He tries to prioritize based on the
customer's satisfaction.
Also, just to take a side step before I go
into this a little bit more, remember
PMI's new model essentially
refers to rather than projects
being processed driven,
projects are now value driven.
So value driven is one of the key aspects
of project management.
And it has been for agile.
One of the key things about Agile is
delivering value early on to the customer.
And that's really what
these prioritization
techniques are kind
of like refers to as well.
Right.
So when you're rating customer
satisfaction, what the K&M model refers to
is looking at what satisfies the customer
versus what delights the customer,
versus what will dissatisfy the customer
if a product isn't there.
Right.
Or if a feature isn't there.
If this feature isn't there, then this is
going to dissatisfy the customer,
so we absolutely have to have this
feature.
But then what is going to satisfy them?
What's going to delight them?
Now, delight, what's going to delight
them?
That doesn't necessarily mean scope creep
and gold plating.
We're not giving freebies to the customer.
No, what's going to delight the customer
would be things like, for example,
we deliver it early.
We deliver a good product to the customer,
and we deliver it ahead of schedule.
that's going to delight the customer.
Anyway, that was just obviously just one
simple example.
But that overall, and
again, with any of these, you
don't need to know a huge
amount of detail for the exam.
We just need to know the very basics.
So let's talk about this next one here,
the Moscow analysis.
Moscow stands for, must have, should have,
could have, won't have.
And this helps identify what's known as
MVP, the minimum viable product.
Also, it could identify the minimum
multiple feature, right?
So they were mentioned in a previous
slide, right?
The MVP, minimum viable product,
MMF, minimum multiple feature.
We'll also discuss it on the next slide as
well.
We'll also discuss it at the end of this
video.
But basically, must have.
This feature is a showstopper if it's not
present.
It has to be there.
You have to have this feature in order to
develop this product.
should have is more of a nice to have.
We'll do a cost-benefit analysis.
Maybe we'll have it, maybe we won't have
it.
Could have is, maybe later, but it's a
much lower priority.
We're not really going to think about it
right now.
It'd be nice.
Maybe, you know, maybe, you know,
if everything else gets implemented,
then we'll think of, that we may think of
these could-haves.
And then what have is we're just not going
to need it right we don't need it now
maybe you know we might need it for the
future or whatever it is but right now
it's not needed right so that's what the
Moscow analysis refers to right must have
it absolutely have to have it right should
have it it'd be nice to have so just think
of you don't even need to think of a
project you know just think of something
simple like you're buying a car right what
are the features you absolutely have to
have in your car and everybody
is different but you know
what's the features you
absolutely have to have in your car,
right, versus what
would be a nice to have.
So if you're living in, you know,
somewhere like Alaska, for example,
right, one of the must haves might be you
need heated seats, right?
If you're living in Florida, then you
don't really need heated seats.
That might be more of a won't have.
I don't need it, right?
Or it might be a could have, much a lot of
priority, right?
We don't necessarily need heated seats
when you're living in Florida,
but you're living in Alaska, right,
then, yes, maybe I may need that.
That might be, you know,
an absolute must-have
when I'm purchasing
a brand-new car, right?
And then they should have, they're nice to
have, right?
Maybe a heated steering wheel would be a
nice to have, right?
And so and so forth.
So again, that's what the Moscow analysis
refers to.
Then you have something called the paired
comparison analysis, and just basically
it's looking at successive pairs and
prioritizing one over the other.
Right.
So, you know, we're looking at these two,
which is a higher priority.
This one is a higher priority than this
feature.
Right.
So now let's look at these two features,
which is a higher priority.
This is a higher priority than this and so
and so forth.
So the other one then is this hundred
point method, right, which is also
sometimes called monopoly money,
right?
But the more common term is a hundred
point method.
And it's basically each team member is
given 100 points, right?
Or if it's monopoly money, $100.
And you have the user stories,
user stories.
are laid out, and then team members are
trying to determine which is a higher
priority user story, which is a lower
priority user story.
And then they're going to be delegating
some money or giving some money or giving
the points to these user stories according
to the priorities.
So higher priority user stories
will end up with higher points,
low priority user stories
will end up with lower points.
So that's a way of prioritizing as
prioritizing user stories.
Now, let's do a quick review of these
terms here.
Minimum viable product, minimum marketable
feature, minimum business increment.
Now, MVP and MMF
sound very similar, but there's
a subtle difference
between the two, right?
Minimum viable product, right,
is the smallest collection of features
that can be included to be considered
functional, where the minimum marketable
feature is the smallest unit of functionality
that actually provides any time.
valuable value to the customer.
All right, so that was the definition.
What does it actually mean?
So let's just give you an example here.
The best way is just to give you an
example.
Think of a bicycle, right?
What is the minimum features that a
bicycle needs to have?
In order for something to be called a
bicycle, what do you need?
Well, what does a bicycle have generally?
A bicycle has two wheels, it has a frame,
it has handlebars, right?
They have brakes, they have pedals,
you know, they have a gear, gears.
So this is what makes a bicycle.
However, what's the absolute minimum for
something to be called a bicycle?
In order to have a product that is a
bicycle, do you need to have 15 gears.
Not necessarily.
But what does a bicycle absolutely have to
have?
It has to have two wheels, a frame,
handlebars, then you can consider it a bicycle.
If you just have one wheel, would that be
consider a bicycle?
No.
If you have two wheels,
just two wheels, and
that's it, would that be
considered a bicycle?
No.
But if you have two wheels and a frame and
a handlebar, then now you can say,
all right, you know, you draw this out,
that looks like a bicycle to me now.
So that could be your minimum viable
product.
It has to have two wheels, a frame,
and a handlebar.
Now, would you be able to sell it?
If that's all, if all it has, would you be
able to sell it?
As a bicycle?
No.
Because it doesn't have any brakes.
It doesn't have any pedals, right?
So in order for some, it doesn't have a
wheel either.
In order to be able to sell this as a
bicycle, then you would need pedals.
You would need brakes, right.
You'd need a seat.
Then that would be known
as a minimum marketable
feature in order to be
able to sell this as a bicycle.
Just having two wheels.
Handelbar and you know, and a frame,
could be considered the minimum viable
product or maybe a pedal in there,
minimum viable product.
But you won't be able to sell it.
It's not actually adding any value as
such.
So in order to add value, we need to add
in, you know, proper pedals, right?
I mean, pedals could be on the front
wheel, just like have, you know,
kids bikes or it could be on a proper
chain.
So in order for it to be a, you know,
an actual minimum marketable feature,
right, then it has to
have a proper chain and
then brakes and a seat,
now we can sell it, right?
Now it adds value.
Minimum business increment
then would be the smallest
amount of value that can be
added to the product, right?
That actually benefits the business,
benefits a customer.
So we add in this feature, it will
actually benefit the customer.
So as a simple example, let's say we're
building a mountain bike.
So this is a mountain bike.
So a mountain bike needs gears.
All right, so let's add in five gears.
Is that going to add value?
Probably not.
If it's a mountain bike, a mountain bike
probably needs at least 15 gears.
Five gears is not really going to work,
you know, for a full-blown mountain bike.
So that's not really going to add any
value.
The minimum business increment might be,
say, 15 gears, right?
Or maybe 10 gears.
Whereas if it was a touring bike,
then five gears might be fine.
So if it's a touring bike, then minimum
business increment, right would five years
might be okay so that's a basic difference
then again very very high level right but
there's a basic difference in between
minimum viable product minimum marketable
feature and minimum business increment
okay and we're using all of this all of
these right remember when team members are
prioritizing user stories right then
they're using all of these different
different techniques here, the Cana model,
Moscow analysis, paired comparison,
100 point method, to come up with the
minimum viable product,
minimum marketable feature,
and of course, the
minimum business increment.
So these were just an introduction and
really, you know, the prioritization,
the agile prioritization techniques that
you need for the PMP exam.